scholarships.com 2015-03-17

# Privacy Policy - About Us - Scholarships.com

_Effective Date: 12/03/2014_

Scholarships.com recognizes that your privacy is important. To demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy and to explain the types of information we obtain about visitors to our website, how that information is obtained and used, and how visitors can restrict its use or disclosure, we have created the Privacy Policy below. The following discusses our information gathering and dissemination practices at Scholarships.com. 

##  Information We Receive and How It Is Used

All personal information obtained by Scholarships.com about individual visitors to our website is information supplied voluntarily by that visitor. During registration, a user is required to provide certain categories of information, such as name, address, email address, phone number, a password, date of birth, gender and country of citizenship. In addition, a user may choose to provide other categories of information, such as career objectives, health or disability information, hobbies and other interests. Scholarships.com encourages its users to provide all of these fields of information so that users may maximize the effectiveness of the scholarship and college search. We ask if we may make that information available to our select list of marketing partners, which are reputable companies and organizations that provide products and services of interest to students and parents. Our users choose whether to opt-in or opt-out of sharing their information with these partners. 

When Scholarships.com shares your personal information with a third party as described in this Privacy Policy, your personal information will become permanently subject to the information use and sharing practices of the third party. That third party will not be restricted by this Privacy Policy with respect to its use and further sharing of your personal information. If you agree to receive communications from our marketing partners and later change your mind, you may need to contact those companies directly. Any updates you wish to make to the information they possess must also be forwarded to the company communicating with you at that point in time. 

Users may make changes to the information in their personal profile at Scholarships.com at any time by logging-in to the website and entering the email address and password they submitted when creating their profile. After users have logged-in, they will be taken to their Scholarship Search Results. In the tabbed navigation at the top of the page, users will find a link to "Profile". By clicking on that tab, users will be taken to a summary of their information, divided into sections. An "Edit This Section" option in the upper-right corner of each section allows users to modify and update their information. Users can also  contact us here in order to request access to information submitted to us. To protect the security and integrity of users’ information, we will take reasonable steps to verify all new profile identities before providing access. It is the responsibility of the user to make all necessary changes in their profile to ensure the information they have provided while completing their registration or conducting a  scholarship search remains current. 

Users of Scholarships.com who wish to terminate their membership, or otherwise request that their personal information be deleted or no longer used, at Scholarships.com may do so at any time by contacting our unsubscribe department. Please be sure to type "Remove" in the subject field and submit the email account associated with your profile, along with your password. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Scholarships.com is committed to safeguarding users' privacy on our website. We require our employees to protect our users and visitors by keeping their profile information private, and expect our marketing partners to do the same. You can feel confident that your user profile will be protected when you visit Scholarships.com. We have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of all user information under our control. 

Regardless of your decision regarding the sharing of your personal information, we reserve the right to share aggregated demographic data and related usage information with our business partners. Such aggregate information will not contain any personal information that can identify any individual user.

##  Information Sharing & Email Preferences

Scholarships.com understands the importance of protecting personally-identifiable information. We will not share, sell, rent or otherwise transfer this information without the user's permission, and then only in accordance with the terms set forth in this Privacy Policy. Our website provides users the opportunity to unsubscribe (opt-out) from receiving email messages from Scholarships.com and its marketing partners, or from having their personal information shared with our marketing partners. Users may change their email preferences by following the unsubscribe instructions contained in each of the email communication they receive or by clicking here. Please allow up to seven business days for these changes to take effect. 

Scholarships.com may use your contact information periodically in order to send you email regarding updates at the Scholarships.com site, such as Scholarships.com opportunities and additional listings which may be of interest to you. The frequency of these messages will vary depending upon your profile, including the types of scholarships and other activities you have indicated an interest in. If you specifically provide Scholarships.com with permission at the time of registration, you may also receive commercial emails. Please note that email messages from third parties are not governed by the opt-out provisions of this Privacy Policy. 

We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process. When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request 

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. 

##  Collection of Passive Information

To gauge the effectiveness of our website, we collect generic information about our visitors that is not individually-identifiable. Our, and our third party tracking-utility partners, web servers automatically recognize a visitor's IP address, the web page from which a visitor enters our website, which pages a visitor visits, and how much time a visitor spends on each page. This information does not reveal a visitor's identity. We aggregate this information and use it to help diagnose problems with our web server, to administer to our website, or to evaluate and improve our website’s functions and resources. We do not link this data to personally identifiable information. We use cookies, tags and scripts to tell our server that a visitor has initiated a user session; however, they do not contain individually-identifiable information. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited. Some of our business partners, such as advertisers, use cookies on our site, but we have neither access to, nor control over, these cookies. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Scholarships.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by our business partners. 

We partner with a third party ad network to display advertising on our web site. Our ad network partner uses cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

We use Google AdSense to publish ads on this site. When you view or click on an ad a cookie will be set to help better provide advertisements that may be of interest to you on this and other web sites. You may opt-out of the use of this cookie by visiting Google’s Advertising and Privacy page: <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>. 

We may share statistical and demographic information about our website's visitors with our marketing partners. This information is only provided in the aggregate, meaning that the information is about our website's visitors as a group and not about individually-identifiable visitors. 

We follow generally-accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100 percent secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially-acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact our privacy department.

##  Public Forums

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, you may contact us by clicking here. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will provide you with an explanation.

##  Social Media Features

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.

##  Links to Other Websites

Scholarships.com contains text and banner links to other sites. Please be aware that Scholarships.com does not exercise control over the information, products, services or policies of third party companies accessible through our site. This Privacy Policy applies solely to the information collected by this site. 

##  Collection of Information from Children

Scholarships.com abides by federal law and the guidelines set up by the Federal Trade Commission regarding youth privacy. As such, Scholarships.com will not knowingly collect any personally-identifiable information from children under the age of 13, nor will children under the age of 13 be allowed to register with Scholarships.com. 

##  Notification of Changes

If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via email prior to the change becoming effective. You will have the option to decide whether we may use your information in this manner. In addition, if we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our website notifying users of the change. In cases where we post notice of changes, we may also email users who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of those changes to our privacy practices. 

In the event that Scholarships.com sells, signs or transfers some or all of its business to a successor or acquirer, Scholarships.com may sell, assign or transfer all of your information, regardless of your opt status, to such successor or acquirer.

##  Testimonials

We post user testimonials on our website, all of which are volunteered and none of which contain individually-identifiable information beyond that user's first name, last initial, and photograph. Each user is made aware of the purpose of their supplied testimonial and the fact that it will be published at Scholarships.com. Users are under no obligation to participate, and we obtain the user's consent prior to posting this information. If you wish to request the removal of your testimonial you can contact us by clicking here.

##  Participation in the TRUSTe Privacy Program

Scholarships.com, LLC has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe’s program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this website, www.scholarships.com. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact our privacy department. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe here.

Scholarships.com has adopted privacy principles that state our commitment and define our policy on safeguarding visitor and user privacy when we conduct our business. Questions regarding this Privacy Policy statement, the practices of this website, or your dealings with Scholarships.com should be directed to Scholarships.com's privacy department. Alternatively, you may contact us at: 

Privacy at Scholarships.com   
Scholarships.com, LLC   
430 Park Avenue, Suite 3A   
Highland Park, IL 60035
